Guide to the National Smokejumper Association Collection 1919-2023
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
National Smokejumper Association collection
1919-2022
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/dept/arch/arch.htm library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 620
National Smokejumper Association
17.05 linear feet and 16 Megabytes
The National Smokejumper Association is an organization dedicated to the preservation of the history of aerial fire management and wildland firefighting. This collection contains reports, correspondence, interviews, personal papers, photographs, films, and publications related to the development of aerial fire management and the activities of smokejumpers.
Historical Note
The National Smokejumper Association (NSA) is an organization which preserves and shares the history of aerial fire management and provides a forum for those associated with wildland firefighting. Founded in 1992, the NSA maintains a roster of current and former smokejumpers and actively collects the histories of individuals and organizations associated with the development of smokejumping and aerial fire management.
In addition to furthering the legacy of smokejumping, the NSA works to support current and former smokejumpers as well as the forests and rangelands they protect. The organization offers support to smokejumpers and their families through a scholarship program and a "Good Samaritan Fund," offering financial support to those in need. Additionally, the Trails Restoration and Maintenance Projects, organized by NSA members and staffed by volunteers, clears trails in wilderness areas using volunteer teams. Established in 1999 by Jon McBride and Art Jukkala, the program utilizes the NSA's network of former smokejumpers to clear trails of debris, build fences, and restore structures in national forests and parks.
The collection contains reports, correspondence, rosters, personal papers, oral histories, photographs, and moving images documenting the history of aerial fire management. The material in the collection was created by the association itself, by former smokejumpers, or by the U.S. Forest Service. The earliest materials include documentation of the development of parachute jumping during the F Studies – Aerial Control Parachute Jumping experiments of the late 1930s and early 1940s by the U.S. Forest Service. The collection also contains: fire reports from various years including the investigation report for the Mann Gulch fire in Montana (1949); newsletters and magazines published by the National Smokejumper Association; collected interviews, obituaries, and profiles of former and/or pioneer smokejumpers; and numerous magazine and newspaper articles related to the development and history of smokejumping and aerial fire management.
This collection also includes extensive moving image materials. The bulk of these materials are from the documentary Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky (also called The History of Smokejumping: Firefighters from the Sky), produced by Stevan Smith for the National Smokejumper Association. These moving image materials are housed on 8mm, betacam, Mini-DV, VHS, and DVD; they include interviews with smokejumpers and both contemporary and historic footage of fires and training exercises. Additional oral histories conducted by the NSA with current and former smokejumpers are also available in the collection on DVD and many include complete transcripts. Finally, personal papers of individual smokejumpers contribute correspondence, photographs, newsclippings, and the personal journals. Collections related to individual smokejumpers are predominantly from smokejumpers who lived and/or trained in Missoula, Montana.
This collection has been divided into seven series:
Series I: National Smokejumper Association Records, 1978-2022, 1.35 linear foot
Subseries 1: Operational Materials, 1978-2010, 0.1 linear feet
Subseries 2: Publications, 1993-2023, 1.25 linear feet
Series II: Smokejumping History, 1919-2009, 2.4 linear feet
Subseries 1: Reports/Handbooks/Manuals, 1940-1994, 0.5 linear feet
Subseries 2: United States Forest Service, 1939-1999, 0.6 linear feet
Subseries 3: General, 1919-2005, 1.3 linear feet
Series III: Smokejumpers, 1938–2005, 0.8 linear feet
Subseries 1: Personal Narratives and Interviews, 1940-2004, 0.3 linear feet
Subseries 2: Collections of Personal Stories, 1990-1995, 0.2 linear feet
Subseries 3: Obituaries, Biographies, and General Information, 1940-2003, 0.2 linear feet
Subseries 4: Photographs, 1949-2005, 0.1 linear feet
Series IV: Miscellaneous Audiovisual, 1939–1940, 1976, 2004, 0.8 linear feet
Series V: Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky Documentary, 1983-2003 and undated, 10.2 linear feet
Subseries 1: Video Log Books, undated, 1.0 linear foot
Subseries 2: Field Tapes and File Tapes, Betacam SP S and L, Corresponding VHS Dubs with Window Code and Rough Edit Tapes, 2000 and undated, 6.0 linear feet
Subseries 3: Other Source Video, DVD, Mini-DV, Betacam SP S, Betacam SP L, and VHS, 1988-2003, 3.3 linear feet
Subseries 4: Video Not Used, 2000, 4 items
Series VI: There I Was! the Smokejumper Storyteller Project Interviews, 2014, 1.0 linear feet
Series VII: Personal Papers of Smokejumpers, 1938-2016, 0.5 linear feet
Subseries 1: Ball, Herman, 1950s, 0.1 linear feet
Subseries 2: Brennan, Robert "Bob," 1938-1942, 0.2 linear feet
Subseries 3: Grenager, Lyle, 1951-1953, 0.1 linear feet
Subseries 4: Kurowski, Ed J., 2016, 0.1 linear feet and 16 Megabytes
Subseries 5: Mathews, Jack, 1986-2001, 0.1 linear feet
Subseries 6: Pickard, Lloyd A. "Chuck," 1946-2005, 0.2 linear feet
Series VIII: Accession 2018-066, 1947-2017, 0.4 linear feet
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
Prior to the materials coming to Archives and Special Collections, the collection was in the possession of the National Smokejumper Association. Video and video logs in Series V, Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky were held by Stevan Smith until their delivery to the Archives in June 2011. Interviews conducted by John Driscoll for the storytelling series There I Was! were donated by the creator in 2014. National Smokejumper Association Historian Charlie Palmer donated additional Mann Gulch fire photographs in 2016. Personal papers of smokejumpers arrived as donations from their individual creators or from friends and family of the creator.
Initial donation was a gift of the National Smokejumper Association Board in 2003.
Additions to this collection are ongoing and will be added by the organization and individual donors.
Eastern Washington University holds meeting minutes and other records of the National Smokejumper Association. Two oral history collections held at the University of Montana's Archives and Special Collections contain approximately 150 oral history interviews with smokejumpers: OH 133, Smokejumper Oral History Project, and OH 163, Civilian Public Service Smokejumpers Oral History Project.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
United States. Forest Service
Aeronautics in forest fire control--United States--History; Mann Gulch Fire, Mont., 1949; Parachuting--United States--History; Smokejumpers--United States; Smokejumping--United States--History
Forestry and Forestry Products; Montana; Technology; Oregon; Washington (State)
- National Smokejumper Association Records, 1978-2019; Series I; 1.35 linear feet
  This series primarily contains copies of the organization’s newsletter, Static Line, and their magazine, Smokejumper Quarterly. It also includes a report of the Long Range Plan of the organization written in 2002 as well as reunion materials.
  - Operating Materials, 1978-2010; Subseries 1; 0.1 linear feet
    This subseries contains reports, memos, correspondence, and reunion materials generated by the National Smokejumpers Association. There are also negatives of photos from the August 11, 1986 reunion at Camp Paxson at Seeley Lake, Montana, some images are identified.
    - Memos, 1993 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Strategic Plan, 2002 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Correspondence, Smokejumper History Project, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Reunions, Includes Negatives, 1978-2010 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Publications, 1993-2019; Subseries 2; 1.25 linear feet
    This subseries contains items published and distributed by the National Smokejumpers Association including their quarterly magazine, trail maintenance reports, and newsletter.
    - National Smokejumper Association Trail Maintenance Reports, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2001 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2002 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2003 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2004 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2005 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2006 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2007 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2008 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2009 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2010 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2011 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2012 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2013 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2014 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2015 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2016 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2017 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2018 (Box-folder 27/1)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2019 (Box-folder 27/2)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2020 (Box-folder 27/3)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2021 (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2022 (Box-folder 27/5)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 2023 (Box-folder 27/6)
    - Smokejumper Quarterly, 1999-2017 (Electronic file Electronic File)
    - Static Line Newsletter, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Static Line Newsletter, 1993-1999 (Electronic file Electronic File)
- History of Smokejumping, 1910-2009; Series II; 2.4 linear feet
  This series contains materials that relate to the history of smokejumping.
  - Reports/Handbooks/Manuals, 1941-1998; Subseries 1; 0.5 linear feet
    This subseries contains materials documenting a range of topics related to aerial fire management. Materials include rosters, regulations, training manuals, and fire reports. These materials specifically include copies of the investigation of the Mann Gulch fire and the fire investigation report of the South Canyon Fire on Storm King Mountain. Materials are arranged chronologically.
    - Aerial Fire Control Project Region One, 1941 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - District #9–Forest Patrol, 1941 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Roster of Forest Service Smokejumpers, 1941 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Smokejumper Project – Region Six, 1943 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Civil Air Regulations, 1945 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Static Line, Camp Newsletter, 1945 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Roster of Retired Smokejumpers, 1945-1981 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Report of the Board of Review, Mann Gulch Fire, 1949 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Higgins Ridge Fire, Nez Perce National Forest, 1961 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Training Manual Firefighting, 1962 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Annual Reports - Siskiyou Smokejumper Base, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - United States - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics Exchange, Technical Report Smokejumping/Rappelling, 1976 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - LOBE Parachute/EAGLE Parachute, Papers by David Gold, SAFE Symposium, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Smokejumper Study, Region Six, 1984 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - "Mann Gulch Fire: A Race That Couldn’t Be Won," By Richard C. Rothermel, 1993 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Report of South Canyon Fire Investigation, 1994 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Fire Behavior Associated with 1994 South Canyon Fire on Storm King Mountain, Colorado, 1998 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - United States Forest Service, 1910-1999; Subseries 2; 0.6 linear feet
    This subseries contains materials created by the United States Forest Service about firefighting, smokejumping, and smokejumpers. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Grave Creek-Trout Creek Fire Report, H.P. Barringer, 1910 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Various Firefighting and Smokejumping Publications, 1912-1945 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - History of Smokejumping, 1935-1959 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Aerial Delivery of Supplies, 1939 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Inventory of Photographs, 1939 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Parachute Jumping in Forest Fire Control, Report of Field Experiments, 1939 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - F Studies, Aerial Fire Control, Memos and Correspondence, January 1940-May 1940 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - F Studies, Aerial Fire Control, Memos and Correspondence, June 1940-December 1940 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - F Studies, Aerial Fire Control, Memos and Correspondence, 1942-1949 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Fire Control Handbook, Region 6, Part III Suppression, 1949 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Air Operations Handbook, Part 3, Aerial Cargo, 1952 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Specification for Container for Smokejumper Backpack Parachute Canopies, 1957 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Timeline and Narrative for Smokejumpers, 1965 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Press Release, Smokejumper Bases to be Studied, 1984 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - C-7 Field Evaluation, April 1994-October 1994 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - FS-14 Parachute Report, April 6, 1995 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Escape Routes: An Anecdotal Evaluation, circa 1995 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Aerial Delivered Firefighter Study, October 20, 1999 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Forest Fire Fundamentals Booklet, undated (Box-folder 5/7)
    - United States Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management Smokejumpers, undated (Box-folder 5/8)
  - General, 1919-2000; Subseries 3; 1.3 linear feet
    This subseries contains overviews and timelines of smokejumping history. Items include articles, booklets, chronologies, a conference paper, and general histories of several regional smokejumping stations including the North Cascades Smokejumper Base, the California Smokejumpers and the Siskiyou smokejumper base. Materials are arranged chronologically.
    - Articles and Clippings, 1919-1989 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Various Publications on Parachutes, Forests, and Fire Prevention, 1930-1943 and undated (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Chronology of Aerial Fire Management (Copy from Malcolm Edward Hardy's Masters Thesis), 1946 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Smokejumper Fatalities, 1946-2000 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Life Magazine Article on Mann Gulch, 1949 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - History of Smokejumping Articles, 1940s (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Children's Stories, 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 5/14)
    - National Geographic, June 1950 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - National Geographic, June 1952 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - National Geographic, 1956 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Articles, 1950s (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Newsclippings, 1961 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Seattle Times, Sunday Pictorial, Parachuting to Work, A Smokejumper in Action, 1966 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - National Geographic, July 1968 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Articles, 1960s (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Outline History of Siskiyou Smokejumper Project, 1979 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Articles, 1970s (Box-folder 6/2)
    - History of Smokejumping by Aviation and Aerial Management, 1980 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - National Geographic, September 1982 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - National Geographic, February 1989 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Articles, 1980s (Box-folder 6/6)
    - History of Smokejumping, 1980s (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Correspondence including Smokejumping Publications Outline, January 26, 1994 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - The History of California Smokejumpers, 1997 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - History of North Cascades Smokejumper Base, By William Moody, 1998 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Articles, 1990s (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Articles, 2000s (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Articles and Clippings, undated (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Miscellaneous, Movie Posters, Various Publication Titles, undated (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Paper by Bruce Van Voorhis, undated (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Untitled History, undated (Box-folder 6/16)
- Smokejumpers, 1940-2005; Series III; 0.8 linear foot
  This series contains materials relating to individual smokejumpers including personal narratives, interviews, biographies, obituaries, and photographs. These materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Personal Narratives and Interviews, 1940-2004; Subseries 1; 0.3 linear feet
    This subseries contains the personal stories of smokejumpers.
    - Alexander, Jim "Smoky," Recorded by James Budenholzer, undated (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Derry, Frank, Death, 1968 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Dixon, Jerry, "Ten Seconds Over Birch Hill," DVD, 1976-2004 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Heintzelman, Jack, Cave Junction Unit, 1940s (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Hicks, Brian C., MSO 95, "The Life of a Lowly Rookie", undated (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Reid, Bob, MSO 57, November 29, 1994 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Rieck, Carroll, May 10, 1994 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Shank, Hank, MSO 47, September 26, 1999 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Stephens, Ronald, Reminiscence, 1947 Water Bomb Project, 2015 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Various Recollections, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Veersteeg, Harvey, MSO 53, Personal Stories, 2008-2015 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Collections of Personal Stories, 1990-1995; Subseries 2; 0.2 linear feet
    This subseries contains collections of personal narratives of smokejumpers assembled for publication and distribution.
    - Civilian Public Service Smokejumpers Life Stories, 1943-1945, Volume 1, 1990 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Civilian Public Service Smokejumpers Life Stories, 1943-1946, Volume 2, 1991 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Civilian Public Service Smokejumpers Life Stories, 1943-1945, Volume 3, 1995 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Static Lines and Canopies: Stories from the Smokejumpers of 1943-1945, 1993 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Obituaries, Biographies, and General Information, 1940-2003; Subseries 3; 0.2 linear feet
    This subseries contains obituaries, biographies, and other general information about former smokejumpers including newspaper clippings and articles. These materials are arranged alphabetically.
    - Burke, Wilbur "Mick," Funeral Program, Smokejumping Photographs, 2000 and undated (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Burton, Ira, Obituary, 2003 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Information Summaries, Astronaut Fact Book, 1997 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Liston, David, Clipping, 2000 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Lycklama, Lester, Background Provided by John P. Ferguson, February 18, 1989 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - McPike, H. Roger, Obituary, Photograph, Resume, 1998 and undated (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Pilots, Various Materials, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Region 4, Various, 1940s (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Rumsey, Walter, Biography, 1997 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Search for K. Reed Harrison, December 9, 1993 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Sisler, George K., Congressional Medal of Honor, undated (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Smith, Kenneth Roy, Obituary, August 1997 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Unsoeld, Willi, Biography, Photographs, undated (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Who's Who in Region 4 Smokejumping: 1943-1997, 1998 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - Photographs, 1949–2005; Subseries 4; 0.1 linear feet
    This subseries contains photographs of various smokejumpers and their equipment. These materials are arranged chronologically.
    - Mann Gulch Recovery Crew, Photographs and Negatives, 1949 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Unit at Cave Junction, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Summerfield, Ed, Smokejumpers Gear, 1950 (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Lewis, John S., 1950s (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Public Civil Service Photographs from the 1940s, 1999 (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Storm King Fireline, Guntar Dambro, 2000s (Box-folder 7/25)
- Miscellaneous Audiovisual, 1939–1940, 1976, 1998, 2004; Series IV; 0.8 linear feet
  This series contains various audiovisual materials including Wilderness Survival Tapes, photos transferred to CD.
  - Wilderness Survival Videotapes, 1998 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Photos on CD, North Cascades Smokejumper Base Honored at Seattle Mariner Game, Sept. 2004 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Photos on CD, North Cascades Smokejumper Base and National Forest Service Archives, undated (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Wilderness Warriors Smokejumpers, ESPN (21 min version), 1 Broadcast Videocassette, 1989 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Forest Service Experimental Smokejumper Project, Intercity Airport, Winthrop, WA, Film by Ferd Haase, 1939 – 1940 Smokejumpers, 1 reel of film, and 1 master DVD copy and 1 DVD use copy of the film created by Photo Magic Video Productions in 2006 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Computers Disks, unidentified, undated (Box-folder 9/5)
  - William Moody, U.S. – U.S.S.R. Exchange Jump, 1 reel of film, 1976, and 1 master DVD copy and 1 DVD use copy of the film created by Photo Magic Video Productions in 2006 (Box-folder 10/1)
- Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky, 1983-2003 and undated; Series V; 10.5 linear feet.
  This series consists of video components and detailed video logs from the documentary Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky (also called The History of Smokejumping: Firefighters from the Sky) produced by Stevan Smith for the National Smokejumper Association. Raw footage includes interviews with smokejumpers and video logs include complete transcripts of these interviews.
  - Video Log books, undated; Subseries 1; 1.0 linear feet
    This subseries contains video logs that include transcripts of interviews and brief descriptions of raw footage with timecodes from the making of Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky.
    - Video log book, part one, undated (Box 11)
    - Video log book, part two, undated (Box 11)
    - Video log book, part three, undated (Box 11)
    - Final edit log book including credit notes, undated (Box 11)
  - Field tapes and File tapes, Masters on Betacam SP S and L, Corresponding VHS Dubs with Window Code and Rough Edit Tapes, 2000 and undated; Subseries 2; 6.0 linear feet
    This subseries contains raw footage on betacam and VHS dubs of the originals, log books in previous subseries provide an index to the materials from the making of Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky.
    - Field tapes 1-39, no tape #16, Betacam SP S, undated (Box 12)
    - Field tapes 40-79, Betacam SP S, undated (Box 13)
    - Field tapes 80-119, Betacam SP S, undated (Box 14)
    - Field tapes 120-159, Betacam SP S, undated (Box 15)
    - Field tapes 160-163, Betacam SP S, undated (Box 16)
    - File tapes 1-36, Betacam SP S, undated (Box 16)
    - File tapes 27-31 and 33, Betacam SP L, undated (Box 17)
    - 27 VHS Dubs with Window Code for Editing, undated (Box 20)
    - 1 Review/Progress Tape Labeled #1 NSA Smokejumper Footage, VHS, 2000 (Box 20)
    - 2 Review/Progress Rough Edit Tapes Labeled #1 NSA Jump/Fire Footage, VHS, 2000 (Box 20)
    - 2 Review/Progress Rough Edit Tapes Labeled "Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky," Part 1 and 2, VHS, 2000 (Box 20)
  - Other Source Video, DVD, Mini-DV, Betacam SP S, Betacam SP L, and VHS, 1988-2003 and undated; Subseries 3; 3.3 linear feet
    This subseries contains additional source videos for Smokejumpers: Firefighters from the Sky not included in the log books from Subseries 1 including various interview duplicates on DVD.
    - Redmond Fire, Mini-DV, undated (Box 17)
    - Missoula Rookie #1 and #2, Mini-DVs, undated (Box 17)
    - 3 Alaska Fires, Mini-DVs, undated (Box 17)
    - Jack the Ripper Fire, Mini-DV, undated (Box 17)